Guide to the Union Newspapers collection, 1922-2010 LAC0013
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Union Newspapers collection
1922-2010
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
LAC0013
14.5 Linear Feet
This collection is comprised of non-IBT union newspapers, bulletins and journals dating from 1922-2010. Included are newspapers from a number of AFL-CIO affiliated unions, as well as the United Mine Workers of America, UAW, the Graphic Arts International Union, the American Federation of Teachers, and the United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America, whose publication "The Carpenter" spans the years of 1922 and 1950. Also included is a long run of Convoy Dispatch, published by Teamsters for a Democratic Union. Topics of the newspapers include union news and events, national politics, local news, and general labor news.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged alphabetically.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Scope and Contents
This collection is comprised of non-IBT union newspapers, bulletins and journals dating from 1922-2010. Included are newspapers from a number of AFL-CIO affiliated unions, as well as the United Mine Workers of America, UAW, the Graphic Arts International Union, the American Federation of Teachers, and the United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America, whose publication "The Carpenter" spans the years of 1922 and 1950. Also included is a long run of Convoy Dispatch, published by Teamsters for a Democratic Union. Topics of the newspapers include union news and events, national politics, local news, and general labor news.
Biographical / Historical
This collection consists of various Labor Union Newspapers with various histories.
Newspapers; Labor unions -- United States -- History -- 20th century; Labor unions; Labor and laboring classes; Labor; Publications
- AFL-CIO News, 1966 August 6 - 1981 October 10 (Oversize 8, Folder 1)
  General
  Published by the AFL-CIO.
- AFL-CIO News, 1980 March 15 - July 26 (Oversize 4, Folder 1)
- AFL-CIO News, 1980 August 2 - 1981 June 6 (Oversize 4, Folder 2)
- AFL-CIO News, 1981 June 20 - 1982 July 10 (Oversize 4, Folder 3)
- AFL-CIO News, 1986 April 5-August 30 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- AFL-CIO News, 1986 September 6 - December 6 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Allied Industrial Worker, January-December 1982 (Box 12, Folder 1)
- America @ Work, 1999 January (Box 7, Folder 1)
- American Federation of Teachers, 2009-2010 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  Includes "On Campus" and "American Educator" Journals.
- The American Postal Worker, 1986 February - December (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Published by the American Postal Workers Union, AFL-CIO
- California AFL-CIO News, 1975 February 28 (Oversize 8, Folder 2)
  Published by the California Labor Federation, AFL-CIO.
- California AFL-CIO News, January-December 1982 (Box 12, Folder 2)
- California AFL-CIO News, 1991 December 20 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- The Carpenter, 1922 January (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Published by the United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America
- The Carpenter, 1934 September - 1938 November (Box 1, Folder 5)
- The Carpenter, 1939 July - 1943 November (Box 1, Folder 6)
- The Carpenter, 1944 January - 1945 June (Box 1, Folder 7)
- The Carpenter, 1945 November - 1947 December (Box 2, Folder 1)
- The Carpenter, 1948 July - 1950 February (Box 2, Folder 2)
- The Chemical Worker, January-December 1982 (Box 12, Folder 3)
- Chicago Tribune Strike Report, 1985 October 28 (Oversize 8, Folder 3)
  Published by the Chicago Newspaper Union Employees Unity Council.
- Chicago's American, 1960 June 7 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Communications Workers News, January-December 1982 (Box 12, Folder 4)
- Convoy Dispatch, 1979 November - 1982 January (Box 9, Folder 1)
  Published by Teamsters for a Democratic Union.
- Convoy Dispatch, 1986 January - 1987 June (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Convoy Dispatch, 1987 August - 1988 August (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Convoy Dispatch, 1988 October - 1989 December (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Convoy Dispatch, 1990 January - 1991 February (Box 9, Folder 5)
- Convoy Dispatch, 1991 March - 1992 February (Box 9, Folder 6)
- Convoy Dispatch, 1992 March - 1993 March (Box 10, Folder 1)
- Convoy Dispatch, 1993 May - 1994 October (Box 10, Folder 2)
- Convoy Dispatch, 1994 December - 1996 March (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Convoy Dispatch, 1996 April - 1997 October (Box 10, Folder 4)
- Convoy Dispatch, 1997 Novemer - 1999 July (Box 10, Folder 5)
- Convoy Dispatch, 1999 September - 2001 March (Box 10, Folder 6)
- Convoy Dispatch, 2001 May - 2002 December (Box 11, Folder 1)
- Convoy Dispatch, 2003 February - 2004 February (Box 11, Folder 2)
- The Dispatcher-Vol. 33, January-December 1975 (Oversize 21, Folder 1)
- The Dispatcher-Vol. 34, January-December 1976 (Oversize 21, Folder 2)
- The Dispatcher-Vol. 35, January-December 1977 (Oversize 21, Folder 3)
- The Dispatcher-Vol. 36, January-December 1978 (Oversize 22, Folder 1)
- The Dispatcher-Vol. 37, January-December 1979 (Oversize 22, Folder 2)
- The Dispatcher-Vol. 38, January-December 1980 (Oversize 22, Folder 3)
- The Dispatcher-Vol. 39, January-December 1981 (Oversize 22, Folder 4)
- The Distribute Worker, January 1982-April 1983 (Box 12, Folder 5)
- The Federal Employee, October 1986-February 1987 (Box 12, Folder 6)
- Federation News, 1960 December 17 - 1970 February (Box 7, Folder 3)
  Published by the Chicago Federation of Labor
- Federation News, 1970 March - 1972 December (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Federation News, February-November 1982 (Box 13, Folder 1)
- Federation News, 1973 January - 1992 October (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Frontpage, 1973 September (Oversize 8, Folder 4)
  Published by the Newspaper Guild of New York.
- Furniture Workers Press, 1985 December - 1986 November (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Published by United Furniture Workers of America
- GAIU Local 280 News Guardian, 1975 March - 1978 December (Oversize 8, Folder 5)
  Published by the Graphic Arts International Union.
- The Government Standard, April-December 1982 (Box 13, Folder 2)
- The Government Standard, January-December 1983 (Box 13, Folder 3)
- The Government Standard, January-December 1984 (Box 13, Folder 4)
- The Government Standard, January-April 1985 (Box 13, Folder 5)
- Graphic Impressions, 1985 July (Oversize 8, Folder 6)
  Published by the Printing and Graphic Communications Union Local 51, AFL-CIO.
- The Grass Rooter, 1957 October 1 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- The Guild Reporter, 1970 December 11 - 1984 November 30 (Oversize 8, Folder 7)
  Published by the American Newspaper Guild, AFL-CIO.
- ICEF Bulletin, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  Published by the International Federation of Chemical, Energy and General Workers' Unions
- Illinois Labor Bulletin, 1955 January - 1957 November (Box 11, Folder 3)
  Published by the Illionois Department of Labor.
- Illinois Labor Bulletin, 1959 January - 1960 October (Box 11, Folder 4)
- Imprint, 1986 March (Box 2, Folder 5)
  Published by the New Zealand Printing & Related Trades Industrial Union of Workers
- International Firefighter, January-December 1981 (Box 13, Folder 6)
- International Firefighter, January-December 1982 (Box 13, Folder 7)
- International Firefighter, January-December 1983 (Box 13, Folder 8)
- International Musician, 1986 March (Box 2, Folder 6)
  Published by the American Federation of Musicians of the United States & Canada
- In Transit, January-December 1982 (Box 14, Folder 1)
- In Transit, January-December 1983 (Box 14, Folder 2)
- In Transit, January-December 1985 (Box 14, Folder 3)
- In Transit, January-December 1985 (Box 14, Folder 4)
- In Transit, January-December 1986 (Box 14, Folder 5)
- In Transit, January-December 1987 (Box 15, Folder 1)
- In Transit, January-December 1988 (Box 15, Folder 2)
- International Molders, Allied Workers Journal, January-December 1982 (Box 15, Folder 3)
- International Molders, Allied Workers Journal, January-December 1983 (Box 15, Folder 4)
- International Molders, Allied Workers Journal, January-December 1984 (Box 15, Folder 5)
- International Molders, Allied Workers Journal, January-December 1985 (Box 15, Folder 6)
- International Molders, Allied Workers Journal, January-December 1986 (Box 15, Folder 7)
- International Molders, Allied Workers Journal, January-December 1987 (Box 15, Folder 8)
- International Molders, Allied Workers Journal, January-April 1988 (Box 15, Folder 9)
- The Ironworker, 1986 June - August (Box 2, Folder 7)
  Published by the International Association of Bridge, Structural and Ornamental Iron Workers
- The ITU Review, 1969 May 8 (Oversize 8, Folder 8)
  Published by the International Typographical Union.
- The ITU Review, 1983 November 10 - 1986 October (Box 2, Folder 8)
  Published by the International Typographic Union
- Kenosha Labor, January-March 1973 (Oversize 3, Folder 4)
- Kenosha Labor, July-December 1973 (Oversize 3, Folder 5)
- Kenosha Labor, January-May 1974 (Oversize 4, Folder 4)
- Label Letter, 1999 January (Box 7, Folder 7)
  Published by the Union Label & Service Trades Department, AFL-CIO.
- Labor National Newspaper, January-December 1982 (Box 16, Folder 1)
- Labor News, January-June 1982 (Oversize 20, Folder 1)
- Labor News, July-December 1982 (Oversize 20, Folder 2)
- Labor News, January-December 1983 (Oversize 20, Folder 3)
- Labor News, January -April 1984 (Oversize 20, Folder 4)
- Labor Notes, 1984 April 26 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Labor Record, January 1981-December 1982 (Box 16, Folder 2)
- Labor Record, January-December 1983 (Box 16, Folder 3)
- Labor Record, January-December 1984 (Box 16, Folder 4)
- Labor Review, January-December 1982 (Box 16, Folder 5)
- Labor Review, January-June 1983 (Box 17, Folder 1)
- Labor Review, July-December 1983 (Box 17, Folder 2)
- Labor Tribune-Southern Illinois, July-December 1982 (Oversize 27, Folder 1)
- Labor Tribune-Southern Illinois, January-December 1983 (Oversize 27, Folder 2)
- Labor Tribune-Southern Illinois, January-December 1984 (Oversize 27, Folder 3)
- Labor Tribune-Southern Illinois, January-July 1985 (Oversize 27, Folder 4)
- Labor Tribune-St. Louis, July-December 1982 (Oversize 28, Folder 1)
- Labor Tribune-St. Louis, January-July 1983 (Oversize 28, Folder 2)
- Labor Tribune-St. Louis, August-December 1983 (Oversize 28, Folder 3)
- Labor Tribune-St. Louis, January-July 1984 (Oversize 28, Folder 4)
- Labor Tribune-St. Louis, August-December 1984 (Oversize 28, Folder 5)
- Labor Tribune-St. Louis, January-April 1985 (Oversize 28, Folder 6)
- Labor Tribune-St. Louis/Southern Illinois, July-September 1985 (Oversize 29, Folder 1)
- Labor Tribune-St. Louis/Southern Illinois, October-December 1985 (Oversize 29, Folder 2)
- Labor Tribune-St. Louis/Southern Illinois, January-February 1986 (Oversize 29, Folder 3)
- Labor Tribune-St. Louis/Southern Illinois, March-May 1986 (Oversize 29, Folder 4)
- Labor Tribune-St. Louis/Southern Illinois, June-August 1986 (Oversize 29, Folder 5)
- Labor Tribune-St. Louis/Southern Illinois, September-December 1986 (Oversize 29, Folder 6)
- Labor Tribune-St. Louis/Southern Illinois, January-March (Oversize 29, Folder 7)
- Labor Tribune-St. Louis/Southern Illinois, April-June 1987 (Oversize 29, Folder 8)
- Labor Tribune-St. Louis/Southern Illinois, July-August 1987 (Oversize 29, Folder 9)
- Labor Unity, May-December 1982 (Box 17, Folder 3)
- Labor Unity, January-December 1983 (Box 17, Folder 4)
- The Labor Page, 1986 April (Box 5, Folder 4)
  "News for Boston Area Workers"
- The Laborer, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  Published by the Laborers' International Union of North America, AFL-CIO.
- Local 73 Journal, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  Published by AFL-CIO Local 73.
- LOG-Seafarers, January-March (Box 17, Folder 5)
- LOG-Seafarers, July-September 1982 (Box 17, Folder 6)
- LOG-Seafarers, July-September 1982 (Box 18, Folder 1)
- LOG-Seafarers, October-December 1982 (Box 18, Folder 2)
- LOG-Seafarers, January-March (Box 18, Folder 3)
- LOG-Seafarers, April-June 1983 (Box 18, Folder 4)
- LOG-Seafarers, July-September 1983 (Box 18, Folder 5)
- LOG-Seafarers, October-December 1983 (Box 18, Folder 6)
- The Machinist, 1969 June 26 (Oversize 8, Folder 9)
  Published by the International Association of Machinists and Aerospace Workers.
- March of Labor, 1953 January - 1954 September (Box 5, Folder 6)
  "National Monthly Magazine for the Active Trade Unionist"
- Maritime, 1998 December (Box 7, Folder 9)
  Published by the Maritime Trades Department, AFL-CIO.
- Massachusetts State Labor Council, AFL-CIO Newsletter, 1981 July (Oversize 6, Folder 1)
  Published by the Massachusetts State Labor Council, AFL-CIO.
- Maverick, 1959 May (Box 7, Folder 10)
- The Michigan Times, 1959 October 30 (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Milwaukee Labor Press, August 1966 (Box 11, Folder 6)
- Model Cities Target, 1970 April - June (Box 7, Folder 12)
  Published by the Chicago Model Cities Program.
- The New Crusader, 1959 September 19 (Box 7, Folder 13)
- News and Views, 1973 September - 1977 March (Oversize 8, Folder 10)
  Published by the International Printing and Graphic Communications Union.
- Northern California Labor, 1982 October 8 - November 12 (Oversize 8, Folder 11)
  Published by the Graphic Arts International Union Local 14 and the San Francisco Labor Council, AFL-CIO.
- Pennsylvania Labor News, January, 1950 (Box 11, Folder 6)
- Pennsylvania Labor News, November 26, 1954 (Box 11, Folder 7)
- Pennsylvania Labor News, June-December 1956 (Box 11, Folder 8)
- Pennsylvania Labor News, November 29, 1957 (Box 11, Folder 9)
- Pennsylvania Labor News, December 21, 1962 (Box 11, Folder 10)
- Pennsylvania Labor News, August 14, 1964 (Box 11, Folder 11)
- Pennsylvania Labor News, August 21, 1964 (Box 11, Folder 12)
- Pennsylvania Labor News, December 19, 1980 (Box 11, Folder 13)
- Pilot-NMU, January-April 1982 (Box 19, Folder 1)
- Pilot-NMU, May-August 1982 (Box 19, Folder 2)
- Pilot-NMU, September-December 1982 (Box 19, Folder 3)
- Pilot-NMU, January-May 1983 (Box 19, Folder 4)
- Pilot-NMU, June-September 1983 (Box 19, Folder 5)
- Pilot-NMU, October-December 1983 (Box 19, Folder 6)
- Print, 1969 October - 1980 April (Oversize 8, Folder 12)
  Published by the National Graphical Association.
- The Quebec Graphic Arts Journal, 1975 January (Oversize 8, Folder 13)
- Rank and File Unity, 1976 July (Box 5, Folder 7)
  "Voice of the Rank & File Team"
- Racine Labor, August-September 1966 (Box 11, Folder 14)
- Retail Clerks Advocate, 1965 May - 1973 May (Box 7, Folder 14)
  Published by the Retail Clerks International Association, AFL-CIO.
- Sacramento Valley Union Labor Bulletin, January-December 1972 (Box 26)
- Sacramento Valley Union Labor Bulletin, April-June 1973 (Box 26)
- Spotlight, 1981 April - July (Box 7, Folder 15)
  Published by the Illinois Credit Union League.
- Steelabor, 1982 January - December (Oversize 6, Folder 2)
  Published by the United Steelworkers of America.
- Steelabor, February-December 1982 (Box 24, Folder 1)
- Steelabor, January-October 1983 (Box 24, Folder 2)
- Steelabor, January-August 1984 (Box 24, Folder 3)
- St. Louis Labor Tribune, September 8, 1960 (Box 23, Folder 1)
- St. Louis Labor Tribune, September 15, 1960 (Box 23, Folder 2)
- St. Louis Labor Tribune, September 22, 1960 (Box 23, Folder 3)
- St. Louis Labor Tribune, September 29, 1960 (Box 23, Folder 4)
- St. Louis Labor Tribune, October 6, 1960 (Box 23, Folder 5)
- St. Louis Labor Tribune, October 13, 1960 (Box 23, Folder 6)
- St. Louis Labor Tribune, October 20, 1960 (Box 23, Folder 7)
- St. Louis Labor Tribune, October 27, 1960 (Box 23, Folder 8)
- St. Louis Labor Tribune, November 3, 1960 (Box 23, Folder 9)
- St. Louis Labor Tribune, November 10, 1960 (Box 23, Folder 10)
- St. Louis Labor Tribune, November 10, 1960 (Box 23, Folder 11)
- St. Louis Labor Tribune, November 24, 1960 (Box 23, Folder 12)
- Time Clock Times, 1959 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  Published by the 10th Congressional District Citizens Club of Illinois.
- Trade Union Courier, 1959 June 5 - July 31 (Box 7, Folder 17)
- Transportation News, 1969 January 4 (Oversize 8, Folder 14)
  Published by the United Transporation Union.
- Truck Trends, 1967 October 31 (Box 7, Folder 18)
- TWE Express, January-May 1982 (Box 25, Folder 1)
- TWE Express, June-December 1982 (Box 25, Folder 2)
- TWE Express, January-April 1983 (Box 25, Folder 3)
- TWE Express, May-December 1983 (Box 25, Folder 4)
- UAW Solidarity, 1962 May - 1985 July (Oversize 8, Folder 15)
  Published by the International Union, United Automobile, Aircraft & Agricultural Implement Workers of America.
- UE News, March-December 1979 (Box 24, Folder 4)
- UE News, January-October 1980 (Box 24, Folder 5)
- UE News, May-December 1981 (Box 24, Folder 6)
- UE News, February-November 1982 (Box 24, Folder 7)
- UE News, 1983 (Box 24, Folder 8)
- UFWA-Furniture Workers Press, January-October 1981 (Box 25, Folder 5)
- UFWA-Furniture Workers Press, January-December 1982 (Box 25, Folder 6)
- UFWA-Furniture Workers Press, January-November 1983 (Box 25, Folder 7)
- UFWA-Furniture Workers Press, January-April 1984 (Box 25, Folder 8)
- UFWA-Furniture Workers Press, January-May 1985 (Box 25, Folder 9)
- Union Tabloid, 1980 February - 1990 September (Oversize 8, Folder 16)
- The Unionist, 2009-2010 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  Published by the American Federation of Government Employees, AFL-CIO, Local 644.
- United Mine Workers Journal, 1972 October 1 - 1977 May (Box 7, Folder 19)
  Published by the United Mine Workers of America.
- United Mine Workers Journal, 1985 September - 1986 September (Box 2, Folder 9)
  Published by United Mine Workers of America
- UWMM-The Union Spotlight, January-December 1964 (Box 24, Folder 9)
- Voice of Labor, 1984 April 12 - 1985 October 3 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  Published in Peoria, IL.
- Washington Report, July-September 1982 (Box 24, Folder 10)
- White Collar, 1973 (Oversize 3, Folder 1)
  Published by the Office and Professional Employees International Union, AFL-CIO and CLC
- White Collar, 1974 (Oversize 3, Folder 2)
- White Collar, 1976 (Oversize 3, Folder 3)
- Work History News, 1993 August (Box 5, Folder 9)
  Published by the New York Labor History Association, Inc.
- Miscellaneous Clippings, 1958-1961 (Box 7, Folder 20)
- Newspaper Clippings- Union Disputes, 1935 (Box 25, Folder 10)